engage with anytime soon." And of course, we're talking about drones, right, a technology that's not only unpopular in the West but one that has become a very, very unpleasant fact of life for many living in poor countries, especially those engaged in conflict. So why are we doing this? Well, we chose to do this one not because it's easy, but because it can have amazing impact. Imagine one billion people being connected to physical goods in the same way that mobile telecommunications connected them to information. Imagine if the next big network we built in the world was a network for the transportation of matter. In the developing world, we would hope to reach millions of people with better vaccines, reach them with better medication. It would give us an unfair advantage against battling HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis and other epidemics. Over time, we would hope it would become a new platform for economic transactions, lifting millions of people out of poverty. In the developed world and the emerging world, we would hope it would become a new mode of transportation that could help make our cities more livable. So for those that still believe that this is science fiction, I firmly say to you that it is not. We do need to engage, though, in social fiction to make it happen. Thank you. (Applause)
hacer hincapié en un futuro cercano". Y, desde luego, estamos hablando de drones, una tecnología que no solo es poco popular en Occidente sino que se ha convertido en una realidad muy desagradable para muchos que viven en países pobres, sobre todo aquellos que están involucrados en conflictos. Entonces, ¿por qué estamos haciendo esto? Bien, elegimos hacer esto no solo porque era fácil sino porque podemos causar un impacto asombroso. Imaginen a mil millones de personas conectadas a los bienes materiales de la misma forma que los sistemas de telecomunicaciones móviles les conectan a la información. Imaginen si la próxima gran red que construyéramos en el mundo fuera una red de transporte de materiales. En el mundo desarrollado, esperaríamos llegar a millones de personas con mejores vacunas llegar a ellos con mejores medicinas. Nos daría una ventaja decisiva en la lucha contra el virus del SIDA y VIH, la tuberculosis y otras epidemias. Con el tiempo, esperaríamos que se convirtiera en una nueva plataforma para transacciones económicas sacando a millones de personas de la pobreza. En el mundo desarrollado y emergente, esperaríamos que se convirtiera en una nueva forma de transporte que pudiera ayudar a hacer nuestras ciudades más habitables. A quienes aún creen que esto es ciencia ficción, les digo firmemente que no lo es. Pero debemos involucrarnos en la ficción social para hacer que suceda. Gracias. (Aplausos)